vlacs.org 2019-10-28

# Website Privacy Policy - VLACS

The Virtual Learning Academy Charter School (“VLACS ”) respects its users’ privacy. This privacy policy was established to inform users how VLACS collects and uses the information gathered when users visit VLACS’s website and online courses (the “Website”). The Privacy Policy applies to the Website and does not apply to information VLACS collects in other ways, such as through phone, fax, or email.

#### Information Collected

VLACS’s Website collects information in two different forms: non-personally identifiable information gathered from the navigation of the Website and voluntarily provided personal information provided by users.

#### Non-Personally Identifiable Information

When users visit VLACS’s Website, VLACS may track, collect, and aggregate non-personal information indicating, among other things, which pages of the Website were visited, the number of visitors received on a specific page, which pages are visited most often, and other “usage data". Such information may include the user’s IP address, the name of the referring Website, which pages a user visited on the Website, and how much time spent on each page. This information may be used to monitor and improve the Website.

VLACS may also use cookies to help determine and identify repeat visitors, the type of content and sites to which a user links, and the length of time each user spends on any section of the Website. Cookies do not collect any personally identifiable information, and users can decline cookies in their internet web browser.

#### Voluntary Personally Identifiable Information

The Website has opportunities for users to voluntarily provide information that can be used to identify a specific user, including,but not limited to a user’s first and last name, email address, and date of birth, on pages such as the “Contact Us” page. The Website does not collect personal information about individuals except when individuals provide information on a voluntary basis. Such information may also be collected when a user registers for online courses, participates in online forums and chatrooms, participates in online tests and assessments, or receives other services on or through the Website.

VLACS may use personally identifiable information to provide educational services to its students who enroll in online courses and to otherwise support its students with regard to matters such as testing, academic progress, attendance, customer service, or for health or safety purposes. VLACS will use or share personally identifiable information if required to do so by law, such as a court order, or permitted to do so for law enforcement purposes or to protect VLACS’ legal rights.

To the extent permitted by applicable state and federal law, VLACS may use personally identifiable information to provide its users with information about new products and services available through VLACS .

#### Message Boards and Chat Rooms

As a part of its online courses, VLACS may offer message boards, chat rooms, and other communication tools for students to participate in as a part of their education. Please be aware that postings made using these tools may be viewed by other students or VLACS staff members. As such, VLACS cannot guarantee the security of such information that is disclosed through message boards, chat rooms, and other similar communications tools. VLACS reserves the right, but not the obligation, to monitor the content of these  communications.

#### Security

VLACS considers the confidentiality and security of its users’ information to be of utmost importance. As such, VLACS will use commercially reasonable efforts to keep its users’ information private. Although VLACS takes reasonable measures to protect personally identifiable information, VLACS does not guarantee the unconditional security of such information, nor can VLACS guarantee that voluntarily provided information from users will not be intercepted while being transmitted to VLACS over the internet.

#### Third Party Links

VLACS’s Website provides links to other websites and resources not owned or controlled by VLACS. VLACS provides these links because they may be useful or of interest to those who visit the Website. VLACS is not responsible for the privacy practices used by other website owners, or the accuracy or content of other websites. Links to other websites do not imply endorsement of these non-affiliated websites or services.

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

VLACS reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Any changes to this policy will become effective upon posting the revised policy to the Website. By accessing or using the Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy in effect upon your time of use, including any provisions pertaining to changes of the Privacy Policy

DateAdopted: January 11, 2018  
RevisionDates:
